so what is computer architecture
architecture in the sense that we all
know it is about designing a building
that is well suited for its purpose so
it could be designing for example an
apartment building or a house and what
we want is for this building to be
designed so that it works well for
whatever we want to use it like for a
family to live in or for a lot of people
to live in or if it's an office building
for a lot of offices to be there and the
employees to be happy and so on so
computer architecture is similar in that
it is about designing a computer this
time that is well suited for its purpose
so we can have a large desktop computer
or a much smaller laptop computer or
even a smartphone and we want to design
each of these so that they work well
maybe the desktop because it's larger
can be much more powerful the laptop
provides some computational power in a
much more constrained space
and the phone provides us with a good
battery life and it's very lightweight
and still provides us with some
computational power that is enough to
for example do web browsing and so on